Adam Galt B.Sc.

Systems Administrator

Email: adam@galt.me

Website: galt.me

Blog: blog.galt.me

Github: AdamGalf

Key skills

Debian / Red Hat / Ubuntu / Windows

AD, LDAP, VMWare, Meraki, Fortigate

OpenVPN, Wireguard, RAID, NAS

Ansible, Bash, Git, NGINX, Apache

System Spec and Design

System Building and Repair

Emergency Break / Fix

Troubleshooting and Projects

Red Hat Certified System Administrator

ITIL Certified

Interests

Electronics Projects

Mechanics

Motorcycle Racing

Android Lineage ROM Testing

Summary

Conscientious, hardworking individual with the highest values of integrity and morals. Well-rounded character with the ability to ally professional qualifications with practical experience.

I am an experienced and certified System Administrator and support provider able to flexibly integrate into roles. Working independently, or as part of a unit and serving as a team leader when required. I am accustomed to working under pressure, meeting deadlines and strive for attention to detail. I hold a full, clean driving license for cars and motorcycles.

Experience

23rd May **2018 – Present**: University of Oxford, Department of Engineering Science, Information Engineering Group. Linux Systems Administrator of the "robots" domain for the Information Engineering group.

Responsible for building, configuring and maintenance of data, infrastructure and project servers. Building and repair of custom GPU compute desktops. Management of networks and a range of workstations (Linux, Mac and some Windows). Backup implementation as well as trial, deploy, roll-out and debug of new software. Technical appraisals of system requirements in cutting edge research environments. Resolution of non-standard problems. Automation of infrastructure using Ansible.

08th **May 2017 – 18**th **May 2018**: RT Systems and Solutions, Witney Second Line Support Technician for an MSP with nationwide client sites.

Responsible for maintenance and monitoring of server and backups in a shift pattern. Investigations and resolutions of technical problems escalated by the first line team. Charged with looking after multiple client sites in south England, visiting sites on a scheduled and emergency basis as required. Worked extensively with AD and GPO, BackupExec and Sophos hardware and software, multiple IP Phone systems and Cherwell ticket management software.

07th **December 2015 – 05**th **May 2017**: Windrush Medical Practice, Witney IT Administrator to a large, private medical practice.

Provided full end-user support to staff, visitors and patients. Network admin to all switches and server racks, maintained and monitored network security and on-site/of-site redundant backup systems. Windows Systems Admin over multiple, physical and virtual servers critical to business operations.

Board member in NHS Primary Care Datasets Project – IT advisory role Technical tutorial article published in EMIS National User Group Magazine.

Education

2019 - Red Hat Certified System Administrator

2019 - ITIL Foundation Certification in IT Service Management

2013 - Oxford Brookes University – IT Multimedia Production – B.Sc. (Hons.)

2008/9 - San Diego State University – Computer Engineering – First year